William Connelly

williamconnelly.dev@gmail.com | (206) 369-0037 | github.com/Williamconnelly williamconnelly.github.io | Bainbridge Island, WA

Technical Skills

Front-End	Back-End	Other
HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript	Node.js Express PostgresSQL	Sequelize Mongoose
React Angular jQuery	MongoDB Python Django	Git/Github VS Code

Projects

Danmaku - Javascript • CSS3 • HTML5 • ¡Query

- Created a JavaScript-based arcade game using Object-oriented programming and DOM manipulation.
- Players deftly outmaneuver and trade fire with enemy spaceships in order to earn a high score.

Good Market - Python • Django • JavaScript • CSS3 • PostgresQL • Stripe API

- Collaborated with 2 other developers to make an e-commerce site where users could donate a portion of each sale to a charity of their choosing,
- Created a checkout cart where users could purchase items via the integrated Stripe API.

MovieList - Node · Express · PostgreSQL · Sequelize · OMDB API

 Developed a film-cataloguing, web app where users can track, rate, and receive statistics about their favorite movies.

Punch Card - React · Node · Express · MongoDB · Mongoose · JavaScript

- Worked alongside 3 other developers to create a mock-up application which allows restaurants to digitize their wards cards and for users to punch them on their phone.
- Wrote the backend API and integrated user and restaurant data into the REACT front-end.

Experiences

Freelance Home Services

June 2014 - May 2018

Residential Clients, Bainbridge Island, WA

• Catered to a variety of freelance clientele requests ranging from house and yard maintenance, to pet care, farm-work, and moving.

Visual Media Blogger - Cauthan.wordpress.com

April 2015 - June 2017

- Created and maintained a self-directed, visual-media blog which accumulated over 25,000 views and a dedicated social following over it's two-year span.
- Contributed over 200 posts including over 100 analytical reviews and in-depth summaries of contemporary TV shows and movies.

Education & Awards

General Assembly, Seattle, WA

May 2018 - Aug 2018

• Full-Stack Web Development Immersive Program Learning to build Full-Stack web applications using the fundamental front-end languages, the MERN stack, and Python.

Evergreen State College, Olympia, WA

2015

Honors Graduate, Bachelor of Arts - Creative Writing major, minor in Literature

Eagle Scout June 2011

Boy Scouts of America, Troop 1496, Bainbridge Island, WA

Achieved Scouting's highest honor, awarded to only 5% of all Boy Scouts.